<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Election on Abigail Lebrecht</title>
    <link>/tags/election/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Election on Abigail Lebrecht</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/election/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The local elections in Barnet: What really happened?</title>
      <link>/blog/the-local-elections-in-barnet-what-really-happened/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/the-local-elections-in-barnet-what-really-happened/</guid>
      <description>The Barnet council result has been the most startling in the recent local elections. Consistently predicted in pre-election polls as a Labour gain, Labour’s top target ended up with an an increased majority for the Conservatives. While the London pre-election polls were widely accurate, Barnet was the only area which bucked the trends. Many have been quick to connect the Barnet result with on Labour’s anti-semitism problems including Labour councilors and Barnet’s Labour leader.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UK Election Data: Where to find open data and interesting metrics</title>
      <link>/blog/uk-election-data-where-to-find-open-data-and-interesting-metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/uk-election-data-where-to-find-open-data-and-interesting-metrics/</guid>
      <description>Most electoral analysis is conducted by academics with University resources and collaborators. Not working in an academic institution and having spent some time researching what actually happened in the 2017 election, I have gathered some useful open data source and insights for election data that I thought would be helpful to share. In the following series of blog posts, I will describe where to find the data and why each bit of data is useful.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>