<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Abigail Lebrecht</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Abigail Lebrecht</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mining Mumsnet Opinions - Tips for Scraping</title>
      <link>/blog/mining-mumsnet-opinions---tips-for-scraping/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/mining-mumsnet-opinions---tips-for-scraping/</guid>
      <description>The R blogosphere is an incredible place right now. From R-Bloggers to R Weekly, there are dozens of posts produced daily on new methods and real world applications of R. When writing any blog my first question is what can this post add that hasn’t already been said somewhere on the internet already? Blogs are often focused on new and exciting methodologies, visualisations or applications, answering interesting questions, yet very few focus on what we Data Scientists spend most of our time doing - data wrangling and cleaning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mining Mumsnet Opinions with R and RVest - Part 1</title>
      <link>/blog/mining-mumsnet-opinions-with-r-and-rvest---part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/mining-mumsnet-opinions-with-r-and-rvest---part-1/</guid>
      <description>Mumsnet is an incredible source of information and opinions. Providing anonymised and moderated message boards, it is an interesting segment of a large demographic of public opinion. Obviously it struggles from the inherent biases of all social media platforms, but it attracts a different crowd and a less polarising tone than unanonymised platforms such as Facebook and Twitter, helped by careful moderation from MNHQ. Data Scientists commonly mine Facebook and Twitter to measure public opinion, and APIs are available for doing this, but I think Mumsnet conversations can add to the depth of online opinion mining.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Moneysupermarket of Higher Education? Why we shouldn&#39;t be totally Data-Driven</title>
      <link>/blog/a-moneysupermarket-of-higher-education-why-we-shouldnt-be-totally-data-driven/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/a-moneysupermarket-of-higher-education-why-we-shouldnt-be-totally-data-driven/</guid>
      <description>Today the UK Higher Education Minister, Sam Gyimah tweeted:
We want students to be better informed about degree choices &amp;amp; the returns - today, we&#39;re officially launching a competition for tech companies to take graduate data &amp;amp; create a MoneySuperMarket for students, giving them real power to make the right choice. https://t.co/pAJV7Iz7Oe— Sam Gyimah MP (@SamGyimah) June 26, 2018Many people disagree with this for educational reasons and I’m sure I probably do too, but that isn’t why this tweet made me shout at my computer screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The local elections in Barnet: What really happened?</title>
      <link>/blog/the-local-elections-in-barnet-what-really-happened/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/the-local-elections-in-barnet-what-really-happened/</guid>
      <description>The Barnet council result has been the most startling in the recent local elections. Consistently predicted in pre-election polls as a Labour gain, Labour’s top target delivered an increased majority for the Conservatives. Many local people from all parties who were on the campaign trail have been quick to connect the Barnet result with Labour’s anti-semitism problems including Labour councillors and Barnet’s Labour leader. A blog by Dr Daniel Allington provides evidence for the link by showing a positive correlation between the increase in Conservative vote share in 2018 and the proportion of a ward that is Jewish and a similar decrease in the Labour vote, inferring that anti-semitism in Labour is likely to have driven the result in these key wards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why &#39;What is a Data Scientist?&#39; is the wrong question to ask</title>
      <link>/blog/why-what-is-a-data-scientist-is-the-wrong-question-to-ask/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/why-what-is-a-data-scientist-is-the-wrong-question-to-ask/</guid>
      <description>In a recent interview on Dataframed podcast, Julia Silge, spoke of her background in Observational Astronomy and how applicable it was in Data Science. Later she gave a good explanation of her work in textual analytics and how it differs from Natural Language Processing, again as a method for observation rather than prediction. I found her use of wording interesting and thought it should have some credence in every data scientists’ favourite debate “What is a Data Scientist?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UK Election Data: Where to find open data and interesting metrics</title>
      <link>/blog/uk-election-data-where-to-find-open-data-and-interesting-metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/uk-election-data-where-to-find-open-data-and-interesting-metrics/</guid>
      <description>Most electoral analysis is conducted by academics with University resources and collaborators. Not working in an academic institution and having spent some time researching what actually happened in the 2017 election, I have gathered some useful open data source and insights for election data that I thought would be helpful to share. In the following series of blog posts, I will describe where to find the data and why each bit of data is useful.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>