<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Opinion Mining on Abigail Lebrecht</title>
    <link>/tags/opinion-mining/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Opinion Mining on Abigail Lebrecht</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/opinion-mining/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mining Mumsnet Opinions - Tips for Scraping</title>
      <link>/blog/mining-mumsnet-opinions---tips-for-scraping/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/mining-mumsnet-opinions---tips-for-scraping/</guid>
      <description>The R blogosphere is an incredible place right now. From R-Bloggers to R Weekly, there are dozens of posts produced daily on new methods and real world applications of R. When writing any blog my first question is what can this post add that hasn’t already been said somewhere on the internet already? Blogs are often focused on new and exciting methodologies, visualisations or applications, answering interesting questions, yet very few focus on what we Data Scientists spend most of our time doing - data wrangling and cleaning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mining Mumsnet Opinions with R and RVest - Part 1</title>
      <link>/blog/mining-mumsnet-opinions-with-r-and-rvest---part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/mining-mumsnet-opinions-with-r-and-rvest---part-1/</guid>
      <description>Mumsnet is an incredible source of information and opinions. Providing anonymised and moderated message boards, it is an interesting segment of a large demographic of public opinion. Obviously it struggles from the inherent biases of all social media platforms, but it attracts a different crowd and a less polarising tone than unanonymised platforms such as Facebook and Twitter, helped by careful moderation from MNHQ. Data Scientists commonly mine Facebook and Twitter to measure public opinion, and APIs are available for doing this, but I think Mumsnet conversations can add to the depth of online opinion mining.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>